《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
欢迎来到韦恩集团
Welcome to Wayne Enterprises.
我有些关于韦恩集团生意上的问题
I have some questions regarding Wayne Enterprises business affairs.
吉姆在哪里
Where's Jim?
法尔科内阁下觉得你不会经营夜店
Don Falcone thinks you don't know how to run a club.
他会帮你的
He'll help you out.
上面那些人利用我们作为零部件
Those people out there are using us as spare parts.
除非我们有所行动
Unless we do something about it.
阿尔弗雷德  你能教我打斗吗
Alfred, can you teach me how to fight?
没问题
Yes, I can.
作为一名男仆  还挺厉害的啊
Pretty handy for a valet.
管家  伙计
Butler, mate.
我是管家
I'm the butler.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：迷失_绽放   DustD   木浅薰   charcie   Silence   夜影章鱼X
翻译：爵士年代蓬蓬裙   草草         特效：宝宝
时间轴：艹明   spohy   Kallen
你戴的什么破玩意
What the hell is that?
我自己做的
I made it.
-是吗  -是啊
- You made it?  - Yeah.
-是什么  -是头罩
- So what is it? - It's a hood.
增添点刺激感嘛
Thought it would, uh, you know, spice things up.
我们什么时候开始戴头罩了
When did we start wearing hoods?
-并没有  -我要不要也整一个
- We didn't. - W-Was I supposed to get one?
不用
No!
后期：灰灰是菇凉          校对&总监：草草
-女士们  -先生们
- Ladies... - And gentlemen,
我们不抢你们的钱
we are not here for your money!
我们要抢银行的钱
We're here for the bank's money!
大家保持冷静
So just stay cool
就不会受伤
and no one will get hurt!
别逞强
Don't be brave!
别害怕
Don't be frightened!
乖乖听话
Just do what you're told!
这一切会比我在毕业舞会之夜
This will all be over quicker than that time
跟啦啦队员打炮结束得还快
I hooked up with a cheerleader on prom night!
你在那儿干什么
What are you doing up there?!
增添气氛
Getting 'em fired up.
90秒
90 seconds.
放松  女士们  先生们
Nice and easy, ladies and gentlemen!
这种银行  总能自保
You know, banks like this one-- who are insured to death,
每天都在偷我们的钱
by the way-- steal from us every single day!
我们也该回报他们一下了  不是吗
'Bout time a few of us returned the favor, don't you think?
60秒
60 seconds.
表现很好  伙计们  快好了
You're being great, folks! Almost done!
40秒
40 seconds.
没有
Nothing!
完全没打着
Not a scratch!
30秒
Th-Thirty seconds.
快离开这里
Let's get out of here!
你们做得很好  女士们先生们  我们得走了
You've been great, ladies and germs, but we got to go!
看见了吗
Did you see that?
那人对我开了六枪都没打中
That guy missed me with, like, six shots.
他又老又紧张
He was, old, nervous.
不不  相信我  是因为头罩
No, no, no, it's the hood. I'm telling you.
该死  我们完蛋了
Damn it. We're cooked.
哥谭的市民注意喽
Attention, citizens of Gotham!
你到底在做什么
What the hell are you doing?!
大家自取吧
There you go, everybody!
拿回属于你们的
Take back what's yours!
跟我来  快
Follow me! Come on.
哥谭
第一季  第十七集
我们是查不出丢了多少钱了
Well, we'll never know how much cash was lost,
不过我刚看见一个流浪汉在玛德琳餐厅吃生蚝
but I just saw a bum eating oysters at Madeline's.
又是个戴面罩的变态  棒极了
Another freak in a mask. Awesome.
警卫是瞎了还是喝醉了
Is that guard blind or wasted?
克莱德拒绝戴眼镜
Clyde refused to wear his glasses.
说戴了会显老
Said they made him look old.
对站在身前六米处的人开六枪都没射中
Missing a man standing 20 feet in front of you with six shots
这才显老好吗
makes you look old.
-谁按的警报  -我
- Who tripped the alarm? - I did.
我们被抢的时候你在哪呢  警探
Why aren't you out there, Detective?
这种嚣张的气焰不可容忍
This brazen audacity cannot be tolerated.
他们没去金库
They didn't go for the vault...
只劫走了银台的钱
just the cash in the registers.
出进不到两分钟
And the crew was in and out in under two minutes.
那个戴红头罩的人还挺好的
The red-hooded man seemed nice.
挺好的
Nice?
他没有抢劫我们的钱  只抢了银行的
He wasn't stealing our money... just the bank's.
之后他又撒了很多钱给街上的人  就像
Then he gave a lot of it back to people in the street. Like...
罗宾汉
...Robin Hood.
呵呵  这银行还有共产主义者
Oh, great. This bank hires Communists.
罗宾汉是劫富济贫
Robin Hood stole from the rich and gave to the poor.
而这些持枪匪徒漫天撒钱
These armed thieves only threw cash away
只是为了脱身
to guarantee their escape.
这是截然不同的  女士
It's very different, ma'am.
后面的这个劫匪
The thief in the back here,
-他一直在看表吗  -是的
- was he always checking his watch? - Yes.
他在倒计时
He was counting down.
他们知道我们的响应时间
They knew what our response time was.
做足了功课
They'd done their homework.
警报最近有没有因为其他原因触响过
Has the alarm been triggered for any other reason recently?
没有
No.
别忘了之前烟雾弹那次
Well, there was that time with the smoke bomb.
烟雾弹
Smoke bomb?
一周前左右  一颗照明弹或是爆竹之类的
A week or so ago, a small flare or firework, or something,
在抵押贷款办公区爆开了
was set off by the Mortgages desk.
触发了警报
It tripped the alarm.
我们以为那只是小孩的恶作剧
We thought it was just a kid's prank.
我们需要你找出那起事件发生时的
We're gonna need you to find the surveillance footage
监控录像
from that incident.
你好先生  有什么能够帮到您的吗
Yes, sir. How can I help you?
雷吉
Reggie?
抱歉这么晚来找你
Sorry for calling so late.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
天啊  伙计  有多久了
Oh, my God, mate. How long's it been?
二十年了
20 years.
我昨晚被哥谭警局带走了
I got picked up by the GCPD last night
因为我想在韦斯特伯里桥下过夜
for trying to sleep under the Westbury Bridge.
-给  伙计  -谢了  伙计
- Here, mate. - Cheers, mate.
一位警官是海军陆战队老兵
One of the officers was a marine, back in the day,
于是我们就聊了起来
so we got to talking.
我告诉他我曾是英国空降特勤队的
I told him I was with Her Majesty's Special Air Service back in the day.
于是他就放过了我
So he took pity on me.
他说  你为什么不去找找你的老队友
He says, "Why don't you look up some of your old regiment,
看看他们能不能  帮你一把
you know, see if one of the guys can... help you out."
好吧...
Well, you know...
很高兴你能来找我  雷吉
I'm pleased you looked me up, Reg.
如果有谁告诉我
If anyone would've told me
你会在这种地方  我都不会相信
this is where I'd find you, I wouldn't have believed them.
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
对我挺好
It's good for me.
我看出来了
I can see that.
我挺想你的  伙计
I've missed you, mate.
想你这张丑脸
Missed your ugly mug.
干杯
Cheers.
发生了什么  雷吉
What happened, Reggie?
温妮莎死了
Vanessa died.
到今天已经有11年了
11 years ago now.
在那之后
I just couldn't find the energy
我就是无法振作起来了  你懂吗
to get back out there after that, you know?
一年后  我丢了房子
A year later, I lost the house.
搬回了哥谭
Moved back to Gotham.
换了几份工作
I've had a few jobs.
没一件正经的
Nothing I'm proud of.
是因为酒  阿尔弗
It was the drink, Alfie.
是因为酒
It was the drink.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred?
布鲁斯少爷
Um, Master Bruce.
这位是  雷吉纳德・佩恩
This is, uh, Reginald Payne.
我们是老战友  少爷
We served together, sir.
很高兴见到你  先生
Very pleased to meet you, sir.
被大雨淋到了吗
You were caught in the storm?
雷吉最近运气不太好  布鲁斯少爷
Reggie's had a run of bad luck, Master Bruce.
我不想麻烦人  我只是...
I-I don't wish to be a nuisance. I just...
我有很久没见过阿尔弗了
I hadn't seen Alfie in a very long time.
不  很高兴你来找我们  佩恩先生
N-No, I'm glad you found us, Mr. Payne.
请安心在这里待几天吧
Please, feel free to stay with us a few days.
您真是太慷慨了  不过...
That's very kind of you, but...
我坚持
I insist.
别客气
Please.
你们要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
这边走  穆尼女士
This way, Miss Mooney.
谁选来的这些人
Who chose these people?
你们从哪找来的
Where'd you get them from?
请坐
Sit, please.
坐下
Sit.
找到你了  红头罩先生
There you are, Mr. Red Hood.
十年间的持械抢劫罪犯案宗
Armed robbery perps dating back ten years.
我拿走了死掉的和在监狱里的
I took out the dead ones and the ones in prison.
恶棍名录
A who's who of scumbags.
他们行动前一周对银行进行了勘察
They were casing the place a week before they took it down.
触发警报然后记录响应时间
Set off the alarm then timed the response.
他看起来挺年轻的  可能不在这堆里
He looks pretty young. He might not be in here.
你看到了吗
You see that?
没有  因为你拿掉了我的眼镜
No, 'cause you took my glasses.
那里  大衣下面
Right there, underneath his coat.
他穿了件工作服
He's wearing a work shirt.
克莱格汽车维修
"Kleg's Auto."
这个白痴
Idiot.
克莱格汽车维修
红头罩帮
"The Red Hood Gang"!
这名字多响亮啊
It's got a ring to it.
-才不呢  -看到这些人了吗
- No, it doesn't. - See those people?
他们喜欢我
They loved me.
他们喜欢的是你丢的钱
They loved the money you threw at 'em.
对了  那事真是多谢了
Thanks for that, by the way.
不如从你那份里扣吧
Shall we take it out of your share?
你们不明白
You guys don't get it.
我们不再只是五个持枪抢劫犯了
We're not just five mooks with shotguns anymore.
我们是红头罩帮
We're the Red Hood Gang.
我们劫富济贫
Taking from the rich and giving back to the poor.
相信我
Mark my words,
这个城市的人  他们懂我
the people in this town, they're gonna get me.
-懂我们行了吧  -你能闭嘴吗
- Us. - Will you shut up?
你到处乱蹦Q本可能会害我们被杀的
All that prancing around could have gotten us killed.
你错了  那保安离我就六米远
You're wrong. That guard, he was 20 feet away from me.
结果一发都没中
Not one shot got close.
狗屎运
Luck!
他显得很紧张
He looked r-real nervous.
是因为头罩
It's the hood!
它给我带来了好运  相信我
It's good luck. I'm telling you.
戴上它我觉得自己完全变了个人
I feel like a totally different person with it on.
你能坐下吗
Eh, sit down, will ya?
我们还得梳理明天的计划
We need to go over tomorrow's score.
不  这让我们与众不同
Nah, this sets us apart.
只是块剪了两个洞的布
It's a piece of cloth -- two holes cut out of it.
这是个象征
It's a symbol!
戴它的人就是头儿
Whoever wears the hood should lead!
他说的对
He's right.
有人有意见吗
Any objections?
那么
So...
惹事的就是你吗
you're the one causing all of the fuss.
如今拿刀的那位
The one with the knife now.
这是你的地盘吗
This is your facility?
我管理这里  没错
I manage it, yes.
但这里属于你吗
But do you own it?
这里属于医生
The doctor owns it.
你去哪
Where are you going?
回地下室  我们没的谈了
Back to the basement. We're done here.
穆尼女士
Miss Mooney...
请坐
Take a seat.
我只和医生谈  其他谁也不行
I will talk to the doctor and the doctor only.
他正在哥谭会诊
He's away on a consultation in Gotham.
那等他回来再找我
Then call me when he returns.
他特地要求我
He expressly asked me
满足你的要求
to attend to your demands.
他叫什么
His name.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
那个医生  他叫什么名字
The doctor. His name.
杜马赫
Dulmacher.
你去告诉杜马赫医生
You tell Dr. Dulmacher
地下室是我的
that the basement is mine.
我不同意  他一个人也拿不到
No one will leave unless I say so.
他和我面对面谈好条件前
It will remain that way until he sits with me
一直都会如此
and negotiates terms.
也许
Perhaps...
我们一开始有些误会  穆尼女士
you and I got off on the wrong foot, Miss Mooney.
你多久没洗澡了
When was the last time you had a shower?
或是换新衣服
A new set of clothes?
带穆尼女士去我的私人卫浴
Take Miss Mooney to my private bathroom,
再从库房为她挑两件新衣服
and then pick up some fresh clothes for her from storage.
梳洗一番
Freshen up.
再回来见我
Come back to me.
那时我们也许能继续谈
And then perhaps we'll talk some more.
然后殡葬师对女服务员说
So the mortician says to the waitress...
不对  是女服务员对殡葬师说
No, the waitress says to the mortician,
他一直这么僵硬
"He was always stiff."
够了  走吧
That's it. Let's go.
等等  别走
Wait. No.
晚上愉快  下周见  先生  好吧
Have a good night. See you next week, sir. Okay.
没关系...
It's fine. We got, uh...
买单
Check, please.
还有什么...还有...
What do we have? We got, um...
纸牌
...cards.
怎么了
What's wrong?
企鹅先生  企鹅人  那个...
Ah, Mr. Penguin. I mean the Penguin. I mean...
-我...  -什么事
- I... - What is it?
没酒了
We're out of booze.
什么  你后面  整面墙不都是酒
What? Hello? Behind you, there's a wall of booze.
那只是染色的水  一直都是
Just colored water, sir. Always has been.
真酒放在下面  现在都喝完了
We keep the real stuff down here, but we're out.
-别废话了  再订一批  -订了
- So, duh, order more. - We did.
只是...
It's just that...
都是马罗尼的酒
It's Maroni's booze.
他最近在生你的气
And he's a little grumpy with you these days.
他以前也不喜欢菲什
He was hardly a fan of Fish, either.
为什么还要卖她酒
Why did he sell her booze?
生意归生意
Business is business.
但他现在对你恨之入骨
But he hates you with a passion.
-他又杀不了你  -那...
- But he can't kill you, so... - That's...
太荒谬了  买酒的地方多了去了
This is ridiculous. There's a thousand places to buy booze.
麻烦就在这里
That's where it gets complicated.
马罗尼为这片区域供应酒水
See, Maroni, he supplies this whole side of town.
没人敢为了帮你而招惹他
No one would dare cross him to help you.
帮我
Help...
滚下台吧
Get outta here!
谢谢大家  再见  抱歉
Thank you. Bye. Sorry.
一点也不好笑
You're not funny.
你看我失败一定很开心
You must take great pleasure watching me fail.
正相反
On the contrary.
九年前我和菲什
I was with Fish
从一个华人赌注经纪人那里接手了这地方
when we took this place off a Chinese bookie nine years ago.
这里以前是斗鸡的
It was used for cock fighting.
那味道简直挥之不去
Took forever to get the smell out.
我在这里流过血  流过汗  也流过泪
My blood, sweat, and tears are in this dive.
失陪一下
Well, if you'll excuse me,
我还得为这些少得可怜的顾客
it seems as though I need to procure some alcohol
采购酒水呢
for my dwindling clientele.
当心
Be careful.
你知道惹恼了马罗尼会是什么下场
You've seen what happens when you cross Maroni.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
看来他们昨晚还在这儿
Looks like they were here last night.
你那性感的医生朋友  汤普金斯
Your hot doctor friend, Thompkins...
-莱斯利  -随便了
- Leslie. - Whatever.
来说点劲爆的情节
Give me the double D-- "dirty details."
一字不许漏
Don't leave anything out.
真佩服你  搭档
Gotta hand it to you, partner.
没整天闷闷不乐
You don't sit around moping.
而是立刻重返情场了
You got right back up on the hobby horse.
但愿你一边恋爱
Let's just hope you can keep your head straight
一边能保持头脑清醒
whilst up there.
钱不缺
You had the purse.
女人也有了
Now you got yourself a nurse.
看来我找到弗洛伊德了
Well, looks like I found our friend Floyd.
干吗  我不喝  鉴证科的也会喝
What? If I don't drink it, forensics will.
他就是戴红头罩的那个
All right. This was the guy with the hood.
衣服一模一样
He's wearing the same coat.
不知道他做了什么  惹恼了其他人
I wonder what he did to piss off the rest of his crew.
也许他们知道咱们会抓到他
Maybe they knew we'd catch up to him.
他是头头
Well, he was the leader,
看来红头罩帮算是完了
so it looks like we've seen the last of the Red Hood crew now.
早上好  各位
Good morning, everyone!
别碰我  我行的
Get off me! I got it.
-好  -我们不是来抢你们的钱的
- Okay. - We're not here for your money.
是为了保险
We're here for the insurance!
为了银行的保险金
I mean the bank's insured money!
还有60秒
60 seconds.
你打算给我们分点吗  红头罩
Hey! You gonna share a little bit of that cash with us, Hood?
还剩30秒
Th-thirty seconds.
拜托  我们很多人都时运不济
Come on. A lot of us are hurting here.
10秒  走...
Ten seconds. L-l...
走吧
l-let's go!
好吧
Fine.
别了  哥谭
So long, Gotham!
再见
Sayonara!
只剩四个了
And then there were four.
人们都会在银行等着这些白痴撒钱
People are gonna hang out in banks waiting for handouts from these idiots.
红头罩罗宾再次出击
我们绝对抓不到一个大家不希望我们抓到的团伙
We're never gonna catch a crew no one wants us to catch.
你可以说我老派  但当恶棍
Call me old-fashioned, but when crooks
比警察更受人欢迎时
become more popular than cops,
-就天下大乱了  -想想看
- that's anarchy. - Think about it.
只要有人愿意头戴红头罩
As long as somebody's willing to put that red hood on,
这个团伙就无法消灭
this gang can go on forever.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我这里有个人  你们也许会想见见
Got somebody here you might want to meet.
-这位是  -我姓姜
- This is Mister... - Chaing.
姜  他是目击者
Chaing, right. He's an eyewitness.
银行抢劫案吗
From the bank?
我工作的餐厅离银行只有一个街口
I work at a restaurant a block away.
红头罩帮今早把他们的货车停在了那儿
The Red Hood Gang parked their van there this morning.
他们跑回货车时  我正好出去倒垃圾
I was throwing out the trash when they ran back to it.
你看到他们的脸了吗
You see their faces?
只看到一个  那个带着头罩的胖子
Just one-- the fat one with the hood.
他摘下了头罩开车
He took it off to drive.
-我去叫人像速写师来  -等一下
- I'll get the sketch artist. - Well, wait a minute.
持械抢劫的案宗已开
Got the armed robbery files already opened.
也许他可以看看是否能认出什么人
Maybe he can look through them, see if he recognizes someone.
也许那人就是格斯・弗洛伊德的同伙
Maybe that someone is a known associate of Gus Floyd.
唯一的问题是记录有点旧了
Only problem is records are kind of old--
他现在的样子可能不一样
he might look different now.
我们可以从中筛选几个符合姜描述的疑犯
We could pull a few based off Chaing's description.
用老办法  让他通过列队辨认嫌疑犯
Get ourselves a good old-fashioned lineup.
等一下  我有什么好处
Wait. Wait a second. What's in it for me?
我被开了很多张停车罚单
I got all these parking tickets
因为我前妻是个神经病
because my ex-wife is a crazy bitch.
我们去想想办法
We'll see what we can do.
在为战斗训练吗
Training for a fight?
只是训练而已
Just training.
谁在帮你
Who's helping you?
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
不错的选择
Good choice.
给我看看你的战姿
Show me your stance.
很好
Good.
打我
Hit me.
再来一次
Again.
不要犹豫
And don't hold back.
狠狠攻击我  孩子
You have a go at me, son.
好了  不该这就被惹恼  孩子
Come on. It should take more than that to piss you off, son.
来吧
Come on.
再来一次
Again.
来
Come on.
别这样  永远要保持冷静
Now, now. Never lose your cool.
否则会害死你的
It'll get you killed.
你想打我  是吧  你想打我吧
Now, you want to hit me, right? You want to hit me, right?
好  挥拳打
Okay. Take a swing.
挥拳打  来  出拳吧
Take a swing. Go on. Do it.
有人让你打
Somebody gives you a free shot,
你一定得打狠点
you got to make it count.
用尽全力打我
You hit me as hard as you can.
好多了
Better.
用肩膀使劲
Put your shoulder behind it.
用全身的力量
Put your full body weight behind it.
来吧  出拳
Go on. Do it.
用力点  再来一次
Harder. Again.
再来一次
Again.
来吧  再来一次
Come on. Do it again.
把我打倒  孩子  来吧  你可以的
Put me on my back, son. Come on, you can do it.
来吧  再来一次
Come on. Again.
你的个头比我大太多了
You're so much bigger than me!
那就把你个头小作为优势
Then use that to your advantage!
打我下盘
You hit me low.
攻击我的膝盖  脚踝
Hit me in the knee, the ankle.
别管拳击手套了
Forget about the gloves!
利用身边的一切
Use whatever's around you.
来  给
Here. Here.
-来吧  -好了
- Go on. - Right!
差不多了
That's enough of that.
你去洗个澡吧  布鲁斯少爷
Perhaps a shower's in order, Master Bruce.
佩恩先生在教我一些别的打斗方法
M-Mr. Payne was just showing me some alternative methods.
是啊  我看见了
Yeah, I can see that, can't I?
和我们的课程大相径庭  是吧
Not methods that fit into our curriculum, though, are they?
是啊  但很有效
No, they're not; but they're effective.
纪律  技巧
Discipline, skill,
努力才会出效果
and hard work are effective.
需要我给你放水吗  少爷
How 'bout I start that shower for you, sir?
不用了
No.
你养过孩子吗  雷吉
You ever raised a child before, Reg?
没有
No.
我也是
Me neither.
这是我生平遇到的最困难的工作
Hardest job I've ever had to do in my life.
让人无从下手
Nothing prepares you for it.
如果我僭越了  对不起
Listen, I'm sorry if I overstepped the mark.
我只是...
I was just...
看得出你在这孩子身上下了很大功夫...
It was obvious how much you've helped him so...
不  是他帮了我
No, he helped me.
因为认识他  我成了更好的人  雷吉
I'm a better person for knowing him, Reg.
过去的事已经过去了
Let's keep our past where it belongs.
就让它留在过去吧
In the past.
这就样吗  俩工人
That's it? Just two workers?
太容易了
This'll be easy.
麻利点  伙计们
Make it quick, guys.
这下麻烦了
Well, this is inconvenient.
警官
Officer.
我们这儿没事啊
Nothing going on here.
是吗
That so?
你们的酒水供应许可证过期了
Eh, your liquor license is out of date.
这批货被没收了
We're gonna be confiscating the shipment.
马罗尼阁下知道你们这样吗
Hey, does Don Maroni know you guys are here?
滚  不然把你抓回局里
Walk away... before I run you downtown.
哥谭真是堕落了
This town is truly going to the dogs.
晚上好啊  伙计们
Evening, fellas.
笑什么笑  布奇
Why the smile, Butch?
先是马罗尼断了我们的酒源
First Maroni blocks our liquor,
现在又是条子
and now the cops?
谁  他们吗
Oh, who, them?
他们是我的人
They're with me.
我总偷偷留几个警察内线
I always keep a few uniforms in the closet.
比进去明火执仗地抢干净多了吧
A lot cleaner than going in guns blazing, don't you think?
不用谢  奥斯瓦尔德
You're welcome, Oswald.
干得好
Nice work there.
你还好吗  吉尔兹先生
How you doing, Mr. Gilzean?
这边  还有那批...
This over here, this...
不用担心
Nothing to worry about.
你没事吧
You okay?
当然
Of course.
谢谢你让我们住下
Thank you for letting us stay here.
抱歉把你这儿搞得有点乱
Sorry it got a little messy.
我这就走了
I was just about to go.
我喜欢有你们陪着
I like having you guys here.
塞琳娜
Selina...
来
Come here.
知道吗  你眼看长成个美人了
You know, you're turning into quite the beautiful woman.
才没有
No, I'm not.
收拾干净
Remove the dirt...
脱掉这旧帽子
that old hood...
和这身脏衣服
these ratty clothes...
绝对是一位小公主
I bet we find a princess undernea...
我有个点子
I have an idea.
天啊
Holy moly.
合身的尽管拿走
Take anything that fits you guys.
这都是你穿过的衣服吗
This is all stuff you've worn?
大部分吧
Most of it.
你一定经常参加聚会
You sure must go out a lot.
以前是
I used to.
跟我来
Come with me.
你真的很美
You're a true beauty.
你可以利用你的美
Something you can use to your advantage.
你的外表就是一件武器
Your appearance can be a weapon,
威力不逊于任何兵刃火器
as powerful as any knife or gun.
是吗
Yeah?
你的外表对你有什么好处
What good's it done you?
好了  靠墙站着
All right, backs to the wall.
号牌放胸前
Hold your numbers up.
不准说话
No talking.
我还以为他们长得会差不多
I thought they were going to be similar types.
确实差不多
They are.
好好看看  姜先生
Look closely, Mr. Chaing.
我知道要怎么做
I know how this works.
那个四号  矮胖的那个
There, number four-- the short, fat one.
-你确定  -他就是那个戴红头罩的
- You're sure? - That's your Red Hood.
扔了那么多钱  一分都没落到我手里
Threw all that money away, and I didn't get a cent.
克莱德・戴斯特罗  47岁
Clyde Destro, 47 years old,
三年前曾因伤人罪和持械抢劫一家便利店
conviction for assault and armed robbery of a convenience store
被判刑
three years ago.
-把他拿下吧  -慢着
- Let's book him. - Wait a minute.
我们只有一个在犯罪现场外的目击证人
All we have is one witness outside of the crime scene,
没别的了
that's it.
弗洛伊德被杀了
Now, Floyd was killed,
说明他们已经开始内部反目了
so we know they're turning on each other.
放戴斯特罗走
Let Destro go?
然后跟踪他
And tail him.
跟着他找到团伙其他成员
He takes us to the other gang members.
然后让他们相互指证
We use them against each other.
当场把红头罩帮一网打尽
We catch the Red Hood Gang red-handed.
没错
That's right.
我能搭个便车回家吗
Can I get a ride home?
如果我从警车里下来
My girlfriend will freak out
我女人会吓疯的
if I turn up in a patrol car.
你真是太迷人了
Don't you look lovely?
还有事情要谈呢
There's still business to discuss.
也对
Of course.
地下室
The basement.
我如何才能恢复经营呢
How do I resume operations?
我们还有生意要做
We do have a business to run.
你那是偷窃人体器官
Yes, you're stealing body parts.
给谁偷
For who?
有需求的客户
We have clients...
遍及世界各地
all over the world in need of such things.
而且  医生他本人
Also, there's the doctor's
也有试验需要
personal experiments.
你的气场真是难得
You have such a presence,
穆尼女士
Miss Mooney.
眼神尤其凌厉
Such a gaze.
你的眼球
Your eyes...
肯定值不少钱
will fetch quite a penny.
你休想从我身上拿走任何东西
You will take nothing from me.
是吗
Really?
在我看来
Because the way I see it,
你只有两条路可走  第一
you have two choices: One...
我们杀了你和你地下室里的朋友
we kill you and your little friends in the basement.
虽然会造成不便  但还是可以接受的
That's an inconvenience but an acceptable one.
或者  第二
Or, two...
我们现在就取了你的眼球
we take your eyes now
看看一个瞎眼女人在地下室里能活多久
and see how long a blind girl can survive in the basement.
你忘了第三条路
You forgot option three.
拦住她
Stop her!
不
No!
我从酒窖里拿来了这个
I picked something out from the cellar.
希望你不介意
I hope that's okay.
你真是太客气了
Well, that's, uh, extremely kind of you,
布鲁斯少爷  但我觉得我们...
Master Bruce, but I don't think that we...
今晚不打算喝酒
that I'll be, uh, drinking this evening.
我觉得偶尔喝一两杯
I'm sure it's perfectly fine to have
没什么关系的  阿尔弗雷德
a glass of wine occasionally, Alfred.
我拿了瓶有年头的
I-I picked an old one.
干放在那里吃灰未免可惜了
Seems a shame to let them gather dust down there.
罗曼尼・康帝红酒
Domaine de la Romanée-Conti.
是瓶不错的勃艮第红酒  1966年的
It's a rather nice Burgundy, actually, it's 1966.
是啊
Yeah.
你父亲最喜欢了
It's one of your father's favorites.
好啊
Why not, eh?
坐吧
Take a pew.
多谢了
That's very kind of you.
给
There you go.
谢了  伙计
Cheers, mate.
喝这酒
Now, the idea, of course,
应该至少放一小时
is to let it breathe for at least an hour.
或者一口闷
Or not.
真好喝
Delicious.
他终于把背包打开了
So he eventually opened his backpack
发现了那条蛇
and he found the bloody snake.
我们都等一晚上了
We'd been waiting for it all night.
他完全不害怕
He didn't even flinch.
-你怎么做的  -就那样
- What'd you do? - Oh, you know,
我把蛇头砍下来  跟大家分着吃了
I chopped its head off and we ate the bloody thing.
真的
He did.
什么味儿啊
What did it taste like?
有点像...
Uh, a bit like, um,
快餐
fast food.
难吃死了
It was horrible.
真是难吃
恶心死了
It was disgusting.
那么
So, um...
佩恩先生  你是空军的
so, Mr. Payne, you were in the Air Force?
特种空勤团
Special Air Service-- SAS.
世上最好的兵
Best soldiers in the world,
如果我实话实说
if I'm being honest.
那么你们执行秘密行动吗
So that means covert missions?
没错
That's right.
战斗开始之前  我们被投放在敌后
Before a conflict, they dropped us behind enemy lines.
我们行动低调
We were quiet,
准确  致命
precise, and deadly.
我们从未损失过人
We never lost a man
而且总能完成任务
and we always completed our missions.
就除了那一次吧
Except that once, I guess.
战争的老故事说够了  雷吉
Yeah, well, that's enough of the old war stories, eh, Reg?
哪一次
What one time?
发生了一场沙暴
There was a sandstorm.
我们被吹散了
We got separated.
两人被俘
Two of us were captured.
你吗
You?
他打败了他们12个人才被制服
He fought 12 of them off before they cut him down.
是不是  阿尔弗
Didn't you, Alf?
我这不在这里吗
I'm here now, aren't I?
这才最重要
That's all that matters.
好了  先生们  我得说
All right, gents, while I have to say
这真是很愉快
this has been absolutely lovely,
但是
I'd like to,
但是上床前我还想收拾收拾呢
I'd like to tidy up before I go to bed.
收拾收拾
T-T-Tidy up?
军纪如山的大兵
Mr. Yes Sir, No Sir.
纪律严明  从来令行禁止
Mr. Queensberry rules and discipline.
多谢  够了
Thank you, that's enough.
阿尔弗雷德说得对
Alfred's right...
该睡觉了
it's time for bed.
晚安  布鲁斯少爷
Good night, Master Bruce.
晚安  晚安
Good night. Good night.
好好睡  孩子
Sleep well, son.
你为什么瞒着他
Why are you hiding from him what you really are,
你真实的面目
who you really are?
我们是老兵  阿尔弗
You're a war dog, Alfie.
你是个冷血
You're a cold-blooded,
致命的老兵  那就是你
lethal war dog, is what you are.
我给你找了些干净衣服  雷吉
I found some fresh clothes for you, Reg.
我已经叠好  放在你床上了
I folded them and I put 'em on your bed,
我还自作主张  给你准备了
and I've taken the liberty of packing you
明天路上吃的午餐
a lunch for your travels tomorrow.
能再见到你真的很开心  雷吉
It's been really nice to see you, Reggie.
我晚上会看到他们  我独自一人时
I see them, at night... when I'm alone.
那些人的面孔
The faces...
那些被我们杀的人
the faces of those we killed.
你呢
Do you?
我不会去找他们  雷吉
I don't have to look for them, Reg.
他们会找到我
They find me.
我去
Holy crap.
你吓死我了
You scared the snot out of me.
我得见你
H-Had to see you.
我等不及了
I c-couldn't wait.
你去哪了
Where were you?
出去了
Out.
只是出去了吗
J-Just out?
关你什么事
What's it to you?
我需要头罩
I need the hood.
什么
What?
不行
No.
我女朋友  她要离开我
My-my girlfriend, sh-she wants... she wants to leave.
她昨晚说我是个废物
She... she called me a loser last night.
她前任又回哥谭了  他是个保镖
Her ex is back in town. He's a b-bouncer.
我觉得她如果看到我戴头罩
I figured she-she sees me in the hood,
她就会重视我
she's got... she's got to take me s-seriously.
你为了找头罩把我家翻了一遍吗
Did you ransack my place looking for it?
我需要它  戴斯特罗
I need it, Destro.
街头巷尾  电视新闻都在谈论红头罩
They're talking about it on the streets and in the news.
-如果她看到我戴着  -不行
- She sees me in it, and I'm... - No!
我们逃出城之前还有一票活儿呢
We have one last job before we split up and skip town.
在你身上  对吗
You have it on you, don't you?
你要开枪就赶紧开吧
You better use that thing
否则我逼你吞下去
before I make you eat it.
他还活着
He's alive.
谁打了你  戴斯特罗
Who shot you, Destro?
-告诉我们是谁  -我需要救护车
- Give us the name of the guy. - I need an ambulance.
待会儿再说  告诉我你们帮的人都有谁
We'll get to that. Give us the names of the guys in your crew.
我在大出血呢
I'm bleeding out.
是啊  你要死了
Yeah, you're dying.
很遗憾  我手机没信号
And, unfortunately, I'm not getting cell reception.
你知道怎么样会好些吗
You know what might help?
告诉我们你们帮的其他人是谁
Giving us the names of the guys in your crew!
我需要一辆救护车
I need an ambulance.
霍姆伍德  爪哇高地  466号公寓
Java Heights and Homewood, apartment 466.
我可能需要人按住伤口
I might need some pressure on this wound.
自便
Knock yourself out.
那是什么  搭档
What do you got there, partner?
一堆被抢银行寄来的贷款拒绝信
A stack of loan rejection letters from the banks that were robbed.
"亲爱的戴斯特罗先生  很遗憾
"Dear Mr. Destro, we regret to inform you
您的贷款申请被拒绝了"
your application for a loan has been denied."
"戴斯特罗先生  由于您的抵押品不足
"Mr. Destro, once again, we must deny your application,
我们必须再次拒绝您的贷款申请"
due to inadequate collateral."
他要贷款做什么
What the hell would he need a loan for?
糕点店
Pastry shop.
少来了  你是面点师
Get out of here. You're a baker?
我很不错呢
A damn good baker.
他们都拒绝了你
And they all turned you down.
那么你是出于报复
So these are revenge robberies.
银行才不在乎我这样的人
Banks don't care about people like me.
大概也不在乎你
Or you, probably.
你得强迫别人看到你
You have to force people to see you.
否则  你就一文不名
Otherwise, you're nothing.
这里还有第三封信
There's a third letter here.
哥谭国际储蓄银行  这是下个目标
International Savings Bank of Gotham-- this was the next target.
我的救护车呢
Where's my ambulance?
敬新的开始
To new beginnings.
我没想毒死你
I'm not trying to poison you, son.
抱歉我有点谨小慎微
Forgive me if I'm a little cautious.
如果这间夜店黄了
If this club tanks,
法尔科内不会给我们俩第二次机会
Falcone's not gonna trust either of us again.
我不知道你怎么想
I don't know about you,
但我不想再做老二了
but I'm done playing the sidekick.
敬不做老二
To no longer being a sidekick.
你想她吗
Do you miss her?
我想
I do.
即便考虑到她对我做的一切
Even after everything she did to me.
或许定义我们的不是我们的朋友
Perhaps it's not our friends but...
而是我们的敌人
our enemies that define us.
敬菲什
To Fish.
她是活该
She got what she deserved.
你在偷我们的东西
You're stealing from us?
你可以直接问我借钱的  雷吉
You could have just asked me for money, Reg.
你不知道求人有多难吧  阿尔弗
You don't know how hard that is, Alfie... do you?
我们给了你一张床
We gave you somewhere to sleep.
给了你一顿饱餐
We put food in your belly.
我有麻烦了
I'm in trouble.
大麻烦
Real trouble.
我现在不需要人教训
I don't need a lecture right now.
什么样的麻烦
What kind of trouble?
你不想知道
You don't want to know.
好  那你把包放下
Right. Well, you put the bag down
然后滚蛋
and you leave.
马上
Now.
你带枪了吗  阿尔弗
Did you bring a gun, Alfie?
没有
No.
如果我有别的办法...
If there was any other way...
得了  办法总是有的
Oh, come on-- there's always another way, mate.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为什么...
Sorry f...
真的很对不起
I'm so sorry.
我是布鲁斯・韦恩
Th-This is Bruce Wayne.
韦恩庄园需要紧急救助
I need immediate help at Wayne Manor!
我朋友被捅伤了
My friend has been stabbed.
阿尔弗雷德  阿尔弗雷德
Alfred... Alfred, Alfred,
看着我  你不会有事的
look at me-- you're gonna be okay.
阿尔弗雷德  撑住
Alfred, stay with me.
求你
Please.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred!
我们只剩三个人了
There's only three of us.
我担心  如果里面有人反抗
I'm worried. If someone makes a move in there...
别担心
Don't be.
我有这个
I have this.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
你们被包围了
We have you surrounded!
这不非得悲剧收场
This doesn't have to end badly!
放下枪
Put down your guns!
去死吧  条子
Suck it, coppers!
有人受伤  有人受伤
Man down! Man down!
停火
Hold your fire!
放下枪
Drop it!
结束了
It's over.
是吗
Yeah?
别那么肯定
Don't be so sure.
我得去喝一杯
I need a Danish.
喂
Yeah.
哪家医院
Which hospital?
我不能失去他
I can't lose him.
他是我的一切了
He's all I have.
他没什么切实证据
He has nothing concrete.
只知道些人  一些日期
Just faces, some dates,
一些新闻剪报
some newspaper articles.
根本没有展开调查的根据
There's no grounds for an investigation.
只是些猜测
Just... suspicions...
拼凑在一起的推论
some cobbled-together theories...
没什么要紧
Nothing.
他有向外人求助吗
Has he had outside counsel?
我觉得没有
I don't think so.
他的监护人  潘尼沃斯先生呢
And his caretaker, Mr. Pennyworth?
他入院了
He's in the hospital.
能待多久
For how long?
如果他活下来
If he lives,
得至少待几周
a few weeks, give or take.
现在是对那孩子采取行动的最佳时机
Now's the time to make a move on the kid.
多谢协助  佩恩先生
Thank you for your service, Mr. Payne.
我们应该不会再见面了
I doubt we'll meet again.
他只是个孩子
He's just a kid.
是个好孩子
A good kid.
再见  佩恩先生
Good-bye, Mr. Payne.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com